I've never studied abroad. I work for
Penn State as [music] a professor. I
couldn't understand at all. I forced
myself to those situations where I have
to use [music] English literature. It's
not to memorize, but
>> you prepared a special gift event for
our viewers today. [music] Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Can you please introduce yourself?
>> My name is Yong Jun Yun. I work for Penn
State as a professor in the workforce
education and development program. Also,
I'm a vice president for TEN Group. my
responsibilities around talent and
organization development.
>> So what brought you to the US?
>> Yeah, I was working as a office worker
in HRD function at the LG display and
then one day I decided to go to the US.
So it was my senior year in 1999 and I
wrote that 7page long document uh laying
out my interests and innate personality
type and the major tasks or goals that I
want to accomplish in different life
stages. So my plan was to work in Korea
in HR function for 3 to 5 years or so
and then move to the US to study in the
field of career development. I wanted to
help 10 million people's dreams uh to
come true and for that I thought maybe I
need to be in a situation where I can be
influential. So one way was to become a
professor. Yeah, that made me to go to
US.
>> Wasn't it a little bit scary though like
having a stable job in Korea and then
kind of leaving everything to move to a
new country? that one thing that I
struggled a bit was whether I quit the
company and leave or take a leave of
absence. But one of my mentors, he was
my supervisor. His advice was just to
quit the company, quit the job. The
phrase that he used was in Korean,
do not leave something behind so that
you can rely on. He urged me to create
that environment for my success. That's
so interesting because I feel like in
the US we always say don't burn the
bridge.
>> So it's a different perspective.
>> Right. Right. Right. Right.
>> Wow. I like that.
>> Yeah.
>> Had you studied English before?
>> Yes. Through school and also when I
worked for LG, we had internal English
program. I attended English conversation
class almost every day.
>> How was your English when you got to the
US? I was able to comprehend the class
content but I wasn't enough to function
as a worker at Penn State career
service. I served as a receptionist and
one day recruiter came up to me and
asked for something but I couldn't
understand at all.
>> She just left out of frustration not not
left the facility but left the reception
yeah area.
>> So that was very frustrating for me.
Also I couldn't speak very fluently at
the time but gradually maybe after three
years or so I felt comfortable speaking
English.
>> What do you think helped you the most
language wise?
>> I forced myself to those situations
where I have to use English. So in my
first semester I volunteered to take
three internship opportunities at career
services. I met with the assistant alo
associate director and asked her do you
have a job opportunity for me? So even
if I feel I'm not ready I just apply and
go for it and gradually you become ready
for that.
>> That's great advice. I think that's a
big part of learning a language. A lot
of people feel a little bit scared to
try something and make a mistake but you
say just forget about that and go for
it. Yeah. Yeah.
>> What about for people who are studying
English in Korea but you know maybe
don't have the opportunity to go abroad,
study abroad, work abroad.
>> I would emphasize that listening is very
very important. If you cannot listen,
comprehend, maybe you cannot speak the
language I guess. So my suggestion is to
understand your own passion areas and
try to watch YouTube videos or listen to
podcasts regarding my interest area. I
kept listening while jogging or walking.
It's not to memorize but try to be
highly familiar with the sounds. At the
beginning, I couldn't understand a lot
of those, but at the end I was able to
understand.
>> But now you're lecturing in English in
front of native English speakers, right?
How is that?
>> I think I'm still nervous in many cases,
especially when I'm in front of about
100 students. My strategy at the
beginning was not to speak a lot. I
prepared the lesson plan and the flow
and then created questions so that they
can discuss among themselves. So that
was one strategy to overcome my
weaknesses. But I have never received
any complaint from students about my
English skills. It's not because I'm
perfect or I'm highly fluent but because
they like the expertise in my area. They
learn something. Now I hope to develop
storytelling skills. Still I think
that's lacking. So I'm I keep learning.
>> You published a book. I've got it here.
Life craft. Can you tell me a little bit
about it?
>> Literally it's about crafting your life.
I put life craft in one word to make it
a bit playful. Like you know Starcraft
uh it's like managing your life plan and
manage your life as if you are playing a
strategy game. In order to play the game
well, you need to understand what you
have and also understand your
environment and the rule of the game. So
it starts with understanding your innate
personality type utilizing the enog and
uh I help people to understand their
life themes as well and their values
life values and work related values and
put those uh together into one sentence
mission statement so that that becomes
their life purpose and I help them to
pick moment in the future that they
really want to achieve and help them to
strategize how to get there and
reorganize
their life to achieve their priorities.
So that's the essence of the book.
>> Can you tell me about a success story?
Maybe someone who has gone through your
program and had good results.
>> I'm maybe the first example. So far I
achieved more than 95% of what I
planned.
>> That's great. So you learned through
your own experiences and now you're kind
of helping other people do the same.
>> Right. Right. Right. One story that I
can share is um a Moroccan student. The
whole mission was to become a leader to
transform or contribute to Moroccan
economic development and also uh
initiate socially responsible businesses
and her plan included completing her
master's degree in China. When she was
writing the life plan, she was not
admitted to the graduate school. But
right after that she went to the exactly
same university the for the graduate
study she worked in China for two to
three years and then she became Mckenzi
consultant.
>> Wow.
>> So yeah she's thriving right now. So
people have enough and what's left is to
connect dots. First step would be to
stop stop and reflect. It is possible
for them to discover what their strength
are, what they pursue. Once they
crystallize who they are, then they can
expand it to different spaces and time
horizons.
>> I feel like a lot of people when they
feel stuck or unmotivated or lost, they
feel like they need to do more, like,
oh, I need to do this, I need to do
that. But I kind of like that you said
you need to take a step back, think
about who you are, what you want, and
then proceed.
>> Yeah. Last year there was a massive
layoff from the federal government in
the US. I offered two-day workshop in
the Washington DC area for the displaced
workers. One of them was a PR related
person. So who had to edit uh those PR
related materials. She found out that
she enjoys uh helping others to
strengthen their writing. Right after
that maybe within a week she started her
business as a writing coach. So it was
really nice. So you do a lot of
consulting about this, right? Can you
help me out? [laughter]
>> Can you try it with me?
>> Can you recall a moment that made you
highly proud and fulfilled after making
considerable effort?
>> I worked as a social worker in New York
City. Before coming to Korea, I worked
with homebound seniors and I had one
client who was very difficult to deal
with. She complained a lot, was never in
a good mood. The whole office knew her
because she called 10 times a day like
complaining.
>> And it was my last day at the job. And
she said to me, "You did a great job.
I'm not unhappy with you. I'm unhappy
with myself."
>> And that moment to me just felt like a
breakthrough. You know, the whole time I
was thinking I didn't have a connection,
but then the very last day she felt
vulnerable enough to open up to me. So,
>> wow.
>> That was a very proud moment in my
career.
>> So, from your stories, what skills do
you think you've used?
>> I think I used empathy.
>> Empathy.
>> Patience.
>> Patience. Yeah. That was a [laughter]
big thing. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And kindness, I guess.
>> Kindness. And what were some of the
values that you exhibited along the way?
trying not to judge community may be
resilient.
>> So we've identified maybe at least six
to seven maybe strength in different
forms. So my followup question is how
are you using those strengths right now?
>> I think at the end of the day I love
teaching because I want to help others.
similar with social work. I wanted my
client to live a happy, fulfilled life
and I guess I'm trying to do the same by
helping people learn English
>> and uh you've been very patient with
many different guests. So I was able to
see that some of my strengths include u
facilitation also one of my values would
be humanity or helping others like you.
My ideal situation is to find those
circumstances like offering workshops
maybe to differentiate your service from
other English education providers. Maybe
you can further utilize empathy.
>> Um so envisioning or thinking about the
potential uh future moments or
opportunities uh is very very important.
So that's maybe the next step. I I teach
a genetic course uh at Penn State and my
goal is to have 600 to 700 students at a
time. So I created an AI platform also
called craft. The platform can provide
individualized attention and also guide
students on a step-by-step basis. It
will be mostly conversational. You can
type your ideas and then AI would
summarize and guide you to the next
steps and so on. My my goal is to make
the platform available at different
universities and for organizations to
help students and uh workers to
understand uh their identity and their
career um path.
>> And actually you prepared [music] a
special gift event for our viewers
today, right? 10 of our viewers will be
getting a free copy of Life Craft. If
you leave a comment below talking about
your strengths or something that you
want [music] to accomplish, we'll do a
drawing and hopefully you can win a free
copy of LifeCraft. Thank you so much for
coming today.
>> Thank you for having me.
>> Anytime.
>> Bye.